<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>96boards for Rockchip SoCs</title>
    <link>https://www.96rocks.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 96boards for Rockchip SoCs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.96rocks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Toybrick RK3399pro board is pre-order now</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/12/11/toybrick-rk3399pro-board-is-pre-order-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/12/11/toybrick-rk3399pro-board-is-pre-order-now/</guid>
      <description>TOYBRICK RK3399PRO BOARD IS PRE-ORDER NOW Rockchip now introduces the new Toybrick series development board starting with TB-RK3399Pro. TB-RK3399Pro and is expected to be shipped in mid of Jan. 2019, in limited numbers.
The TB-RK3399Pro development board is equipped with the super-performance AI processor RK3399Pro, which has superior general-purpose computing performance. It equips ARM big.LITTLE architecture, dual-core Cortex-A72 + quad-core Cortex-A53, with technical leadership in overall performance and power consumption; quad-core ARM high-end GPU Mali-T860, integrates multiple bandwidth compression technology, providing overall excellent performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RK3399pro update and RK1808 introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/09/23/rk3399pro-update-and-rk1808-introduce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/09/23/rk3399pro-update-and-rk1808-introduce/</guid>
      <description>RK3399 Pro update When Rockhip released RK3399 Pro, their first chip with a powerful dedicated NPU up to 2.4TOPs performance, it was told that the release time is August. Apparently they had some delay, and it&amp;rsquo;s the end of Sep now! We recently have some updates from Rockchip that we can start to design boards based on RK3399 Pro now.
Not pin-to-pin compatible We posted on our website that RK3399 Pro was pin-to-pin compatibble with RK3399 and we can upgrade current boards without hardware changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcement from Linaro Connect HKG18</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/03/19/linaro-connect-hkg18-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/03/19/linaro-connect-hkg18-keynote/</guid>
      <description>About Linaro Connect Linaro Connect is one of the biggest event in ARM eco-system, topics includes open source software development for Linux, tools and the various vertical segment ecosystems that use Arm processors. Linaro Connect is hosted twice(in spring and autumn) in a year, the 2018 spring Linaro Connect is hosted in Hong Kong. All the slides and resources of Linaro Connect HKG18 can be found here.
Announcement from Linaro Connect HKG18 George Grey, Linaro CEO, has presented the openning keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockchip announced RK3399Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/01/08/rockchip-rk3399pro-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/01/08/rockchip-rk3399pro-announcement/</guid>
      <description>RK3399 Pro is released! Rockhip released their first processor for AI - RK3399pro, is a new upgrade version of RK3399 with a powerful NPU with up to 2.4TOPs performance!
According to Rockchip, RK3399Pro has the advantages of high performance, low power consumption and easily development.
 Superior AI computing performance:
 Integrated NPU neural network processor 8bit/16bit processing supported Computing performance up to 2.4TOPs Designed for various AI applications including smart vision and smart audio  Powerful general-purpose computing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock960 Linux Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/11/02/rock960-linux-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/11/02/rock960-linux-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>Rock960 Linux Benchmarks Last week, our friends, CNXSoft write a post about the linux benchmarks with among some popular arm boards and intel devices - &amp;ldquo;Linux Benchmarks – Intel J3455 Apollo Lake vs Z3735F Bay Trail vs RK3399 and Other ARM Platforms&amp;rdquo;. The result seems not very good for RK3399 on another board, and also there are some comments of users complaining that RK3399 performance let them down. So we ran the benchmark on rock960, let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock960 Poster</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/25/rock960-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/25/rock960-poster/</guid>
      <description>Rock960 Poster We have quickly made a poster for rock960. This was initial for the announcement at the SFO17 Linaro Connect. You can download the full pdf version here.
Update:
Some engineers and the VP of Rockchip, Chen Feng, shared this poster at their Wechat Moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour to the factory</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/24/a-tour-to-the-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 09:20:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/24/a-tour-to-the-factory/</guid>
      <description>A tour to the factory After long preparation and in house design, we are finnally ready to start the first sample production for rock960. We visited the factory yesterday and brought back some fresh media to share with you.
SMT production line
The SMT, Surface Mount Technology, glue two parts together, the PCB and the components(chips and connectors).
Samsung SMT machine
RK3399 and bare PCBs
The number of the sample is 10, with 2GB ram and 4GB ram variants, each 5pcs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello rock960</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/10/hello-rock960/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/10/hello-rock960/</guid>
      <description>Rock960 layout Hello, here comes the rock960, a Rockchip RK3399 based single board computer which is compliant for the 96boards CE specification.
The screenshot below shows the basic layout of the board, with major SoC, dram, emmc and connectors in place.
Considering that the 96boards CE specification of board size is only 85mm x 54mm, the actually size is really small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Keep in touch The team behind 96rocks is Vamrs, an embedded solution provider based in Shenzhen, China. The 96rocks project aims at providing a fundamental hardware platform for the commercial and industrial applications. We believe that an open eco-system and open source community benefit everyone.
Please feel free to contact us, we are happy to answer any 96rocks/96boards questions from you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/faq/</guid>
      <description>Frequently asked questions for 96rocks.
1. What is 96boards? 96Boards is an open hardware specification for ARM 32-bit and 64-bit developer boards(SBC, Single Board Computer), and a Community Program for software delivery to developers, makers and OEMs
The orgnization behind 96boards is Linaro Ltd, a not-for-profit engineering organization developing open source software for the ARM® architecture.
2. What is 96rocks? 96rocks is a project about 96boards for Rockchip SoCs. Rockchip is one of the major ARM SoC designers in China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre Order</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/preorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/preorder/</guid>
      <description>Loading... </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RK3399pro Update</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/rk3399pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/rk3399pro/</guid>
      <description>Loading... </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>