<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>default on 96boards for Rockchip SoCs</title>
    <link>https://www.96rocks.com/categories/default/</link>
    <description>Recent content in default on 96boards for Rockchip SoCs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.96rocks.com/categories/default/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockchip RK3566 features and highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2020/10/21/rockchip-rk3566-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2020/10/21/rockchip-rk3566-highlights/</guid>
      <description>In the Rockchip 2020 Processor Roadmap Update we had some basic info for RK3566 SoC and we know it&amp;rsquo;s a mid-range SoC targeting at AIoT applications with quad A55 cores, G52 GPU and supports dual display. We also regarded RK3566 as an upgrade version of the classic RK3288 with 64bits cpu, up to date gpu and some modern peripheral such as USB3.0. Vamrs, as the tier one design house of Rockchip, now have received the reference design of RK3566 and we can&amp;rsquo;t wait to share with you some highlights of this amazing and promising SoC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenGLES 3 Demo on the Rock960 running Panfrost drivers</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2020/05/28/opengles-3-demo-on-the-rock960-running-panfrost-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2020/05/28/opengles-3-demo-on-the-rock960-running-panfrost-drivers/</guid>
      <description>OpenGLES 3 Demo on the Rock960 running Panfrost drivers Sahaj Sarup from Linaro wrote a blog update on 96boards wesite.
Hi all,
Just a quick blog showing OpenGLES 3 applications now running on the Rock960 using the Panfrost GPU drivers.
A Quick Recap on Panfrost: Panfrost is a free and open source driver for Mali Midgard and Bifrost GPUs.
The driver is capable of running a few demos and has been upstream to Mesa &amp;amp; Linux (currently in linux-next).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockchip 2020 Processor Roadmap Update</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2019/11/25/rockchip-2020-roadmap-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2019/11/25/rockchip-2020-roadmap-update/</guid>
      <description>2020 Roadmap update from Rockchip 2019 is coming to an end, and the plan for the coming year is already in place. We would like to share with you the next generation of RK35XX series SoCs, which will be launched by Rockchip in 2020: RK3588, RK3566 and RK3530, as well as its application scenarios, which covers industrial, AI, IoT, Audio and so on. Below is an updated roadmap from Rockchip officially:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduce VMARC RK3399Pro SOM and Ficus2 Carrier Board</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2019/09/11/introduce-vamrc-rk3399pro-som-and-ficus2-carrier-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2019/09/11/introduce-vamrc-rk3399pro-som-and-ficus2-carrier-board/</guid>
      <description>VMARC SoM Family VMARC SoM is a series of SoM(System on Module) designed by Vamrs following the SMARC 2.0((Smart Mobility Architecture) standard. The SMARC standard is a versatile small form factor computer Module definition targeting applications that require low power, low costs, and high performance. VMARC SoM stand out with rich choice of computing power, graphics, camera, sound, network and optional wireless interfaces, offering embedded system developers a complete, off-the-shelf, upgradeable, credit-card sized embedded computing core that is ideal for IoT, multimedia, low-power graphics-intensive applications and AI enabled devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockchip roadmap update: new RK3588/RK3530 and many more</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2019/04/24/rockchip-roadmap-rk3588-rk3530-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2019/04/24/rockchip-roadmap-rk3588-rk3530-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Rockchip Developer Conference 2019 Spring On April 23, the fourth “Spring Developer Event” of Rockchip was officially held in Fuzhou, China. The theme of this year&amp;rsquo;s conference is “Smart Chip, Smart Futures”, and many well-known companies and partners with global influence attended this event, attracting more than 1,000 developers and engineers.
Rockchip 2019-2020 Roadmap Unvieled From the scale of the event, the level and breadth of the guests, as well as the number of engineers, is enough to prove the true influence of Rockchip in the industry!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toybrick RK3399pro board is pre-order now</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/12/11/toybrick-rk3399pro-board-is-pre-order-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/12/11/toybrick-rk3399pro-board-is-pre-order-now/</guid>
      <description>TOYBRICK RK3399PRO BOARD IS PRE-ORDER NOW Rockchip now introduces the new Toybrick series development board starting with TB-RK3399Pro. TB-RK3399Pro and is expected to be shipped in mid of Jan. 2019, in limited numbers.
The TB-RK3399Pro development board is equipped with the super-performance AI processor RK3399Pro, which has superior general-purpose computing performance. It equips ARM big.LITTLE architecture, dual-core Cortex-A72 + quad-core Cortex-A53, with technical leadership in overall performance and power consumption; quad-core ARM high-end GPU Mali-T860, integrates multiple bandwidth compression technology, providing overall excellent performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RK3399pro update and RK1808 introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/09/23/rk3399pro-update-and-rk1808-introduce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/09/23/rk3399pro-update-and-rk1808-introduce/</guid>
      <description>RK3399 Pro update When Rockhip released RK3399 Pro, their first chip with a powerful dedicated NPU up to 2.4TOPs performance, it was told that the release time is August. Apparently they had some delay, and it&amp;rsquo;s the end of Sep now! We recently have some updates from Rockchip that we can start to design boards based on RK3399 Pro now.
Not pin-to-pin compatible We posted on our website that RK3399 Pro was pin-to-pin compatibble with RK3399 and we can upgrade current boards without hardware changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcement from Linaro Connect HKG18</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/03/19/linaro-connect-hkg18-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/03/19/linaro-connect-hkg18-keynote/</guid>
      <description>About Linaro Connect Linaro Connect is one of the biggest event in ARM eco-system, topics includes open source software development for Linux, tools and the various vertical segment ecosystems that use Arm processors. Linaro Connect is hosted twice(in spring and autumn) in a year, the 2018 spring Linaro Connect is hosted in Hong Kong. All the slides and resources of Linaro Connect HKG18 can be found here.
Announcement from Linaro Connect HKG18 George Grey, Linaro CEO, has presented the openning keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockchip announced RK3399Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/01/08/rockchip-rk3399pro-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2018/01/08/rockchip-rk3399pro-announcement/</guid>
      <description>RK3399 Pro is released! Rockhip released their first processor for AI - RK3399pro, is a new upgrade version of RK3399 with a powerful NPU with up to 2.4TOPs performance!
According to Rockchip, RK3399Pro has the advantages of high performance, low power consumption and easily development.
 Superior AI computing performance:
 Integrated NPU neural network processor 8bit/16bit processing supported Computing performance up to 2.4TOPs Designed for various AI applications including smart vision and smart audio  Powerful general-purpose computing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock960 Linux Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/11/02/rock960-linux-benchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/11/02/rock960-linux-benchmarks/</guid>
      <description>Rock960 Linux Benchmarks Last week, our friends, CNXSoft write a post about the linux benchmarks with among some popular arm boards and intel devices - &amp;ldquo;Linux Benchmarks – Intel J3455 Apollo Lake vs Z3735F Bay Trail vs RK3399 and Other ARM Platforms&amp;rdquo;. The result seems not very good for RK3399 on another board, and also there are some comments of users complaining that RK3399 performance let them down. So we ran the benchmark on rock960, let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock960 Poster</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/25/rock960-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/25/rock960-poster/</guid>
      <description>Rock960 Poster We have quickly made a poster for rock960. This was initial for the announcement at the SFO17 Linaro Connect. You can download the full pdf version here.
Update:
Some engineers and the VP of Rockchip, Chen Feng, shared this poster at their Wechat Moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tour to the factory</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/24/a-tour-to-the-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 09:20:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/24/a-tour-to-the-factory/</guid>
      <description>A tour to the factory After long preparation and in house design, we are finnally ready to start the first sample production for rock960. We visited the factory yesterday and brought back some fresh media to share with you.
SMT production line
The SMT, Surface Mount Technology, glue two parts together, the PCB and the components(chips and connectors).
Samsung SMT machine
RK3399 and bare PCBs
The number of the sample is 10, with 2GB ram and 4GB ram variants, each 5pcs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello rock960</title>
      <link>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/10/hello-rock960/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.96rocks.com/blog/2017/09/10/hello-rock960/</guid>
      <description>Rock960 layout Hello, here comes the rock960, a Rockchip RK3399 based single board computer which is compliant for the 96boards CE specification.
The screenshot below shows the basic layout of the board, with major SoC, dram, emmc and connectors in place.
Considering that the 96boards CE specification of board size is only 85mm x 54mm, the actually size is really small.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>